<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<usergroup xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../xsd/usergroup.xsd">
    <name>NODE+CODE (Processing Frankfurt)</name>
    <nickname>N+C</nickname>
    <description>NODE+CODE is a monthly meetup from the communities of VVVV, Processing and related frameworks. We are
        interested in discussing what the things are and mean that we build with these frameworks (and other digital
        means). Since late 2011 we regularly invite artists, thinkers, hackers, ..., to present their views or works and
        to help us start new discussions and open new fields.

        NODE+CODE is a cooperation between [basis Frankfurt](http://basis-frankfurt.de/) and [NODE Forum for Digital
        Arts](http://node.vvvv.org/).

        NODE+CODE is part of [Processing Cities](http://www.processingcities.org/).
    </description>
    <url>http://www.meetup.com/NODE-CODE-Frankfurt</url>
    <tags>
        <tag>VVVV</tag>
        <tag>Processing</tag>
    </tags>
    <contact>
        <twitter>@p5v4ffm</twitter>
        <facebook>https://www.facebook.com/pvvvv.frankfurt</facebook>
    </contact>
    <schedule>
        <meeting>
            <time>2014-04-24T19:00:00+02:00</time>
            <name>NODE+CODE _ field framework with Nick Rothwell</name>
            <description>We are entering a series of meetups that revolve around the theme of "embodiment" as it relates
                to technology, code, digital art and the other things we do.

                The first talk in this series is by [Nick Rothwell](http://www.cassiel.com/), a composer, performer,
                software architect, programmer
                and sound artist. Nick is going to introduce the [field framework](http://openendedgroup.com/field/) by
                the OpenEndedGroup through a set of
                projects that he worked on.

                Nick has a long history of projects that relate to dance and performance. He has worked with major
                companies in that field and on large installations. Please see his website for a detailed list.

                The field framework has long been sort of a ghost in the area of creative coding environments. It is
                very unique as it is a true polyglot (Java, Python, Clojure, ...) system that enables both visual and
                text based (live) coding.
            </description>
            <location>
                <name>basis Frankfurt</name>
                <url>http://www.basis-frankfurt.de/de/standorte</url>
                <street>Gutleutstraße 8-12</street>
                <zip>60329</zip>
                <city>Frankfurt</city>
            </location>
        </meeting>
        <meeting>
            <time>2013-08-27T19:00:00+02:00</time>
            <name>NODE+CODE August - ReCode</name>
            <description>We have Matthew Epler, initiator of the [ReCode project](http://recodeproject.com/), for a
                Skype talk from NYC with us at [DAM Gallery Frankfurt](http://goo.gl/maps/zw5Ai). Matthew has set up a
                website to invite people to
                get to know and translate works by early digital artists like Manfred Mohr into the Processing
                programming language based on scans from old [Computer Graphics and
                Art](http://toplap.org/pdfs-of-computer-graphics-and-art/) magazines. Any work translated
                there receives an open source license and can be accessed and remixed through the website. ReCode is an
                attempt to spread, analyse and preserve early artistic work of digital nature - an honourly
                intent, if there wasn't the ambigious relationship between originality and open access. Additionally, we
                will discuss if reverse engineering in this case is possible considering that we have just one possible
                artifact, the one software generated plotter print. Can this be a proper reconstruction of a whole
                computer artwork? Together with Wolf Lieser, gallerist of DAM, we will be discussing the position,
                possible scepticism and reluctance of artists whose work is recoded. Join us at NODE + CODE's August
                edition!
            </description>
            <url>http://www.meetup.com/NODE-CODE-Frankfurt/events/132310702/</url>
            <location>
                <name>DAM Galerie</name>
                <url>http://www.dam-gallery.de/index.php?id=60</url>
                <publictransport>Underground: Willy-Brandt-Platz, Train: Hauptbahnhof Frankfurt</publictransport>
                <street>Gutleutstraße 17</street>
                <zip>60329</zip>
                <city>Frankfurt</city>
            </location>
        </meeting>
    </schedule>
</usergroup>
