<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<usergroup xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
           xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../xsd/usergroup.xsd">
    <name>Vaadin Frankfurt</name>
    <description>Building awesome web apps in Java? Using Vaadin or GWT? Let's share thoughts on Vaadin, GWT and web app
        development. Meetings are filled with presentations and debate on where these technologies are going, what can
        be done with them and what would be the best practices for using them.
    </description>
    <url>http://www.meetup.com/Vaadin-Frankfurt/</url>
    <tags>
        <tag>Vaadin</tag>
        <tag>Java</tag>
        <tag>GWT</tag>
    </tags>
    <schedule>
        <meeting>
            <time>2014-06-12T19:00:00+02:00</time>
            <name>Vaadin Frankfurt - Drittes Meetup</name>
            <description>
				Entwickeln Sie Webanwendungen mit Vaadin oder möchten Sie dies in Zukunft tun? Dann kommen Sie doch zu 
				unserem Meetup in Frankfurt am Main.
				Es ist mal wieder so weit. Die codecentric AG veranstaltet das 3. offizielle Vaadin Meetup. Hier können
				Sie sich mit anderen Gleichgesinnten über alle Themen rund um Vaadin austauschen. Vom Einsteiger bis zum
				absoluten Experten sind hier alle willkommen. Wir wollen uns über Erfahrungen und Best Practices
				austauschen. Des Weiteren möchten wir gemeinsam über Probleme und Lösungen aus der täglichen Arbeit mit
				Vaadin diskutieren. Das Meetup beginnt mit einer kurzen, lockeren Vorstellungsrunde und einem kleinen
				Vortrag über ein Thema aus dem Bereich Anwendungsarchitektur. Sie sind natürlich herzlich dazu eingeladen
				eigene Themen mitzubringen, die wir im Laufe des Abends diskutieren können.
				Getränke und Essen werden von der codecentric AG gesponsort.
            </description>
            <url>https://www.xing.com/events/3-vaadin-meetup-frankfurt-main-1405140</url>
            <location>
                <name>Die Zentrale</name>
                <street>Berger Str. 175</street>
                <zip>60385</zip>
                <city>Frankfurt</city>
            </location>
        </meeting>
        <meeting>
            <time>2013-12-17T17:30:00</time>
            <name>Vaadin Frankfurt - First meetup</name>
            <description>Lets have the first Vaadin meet-up at the same evening we are having the GWT.create venue.
                After the meet-up everyone is free to join the GWT.create venue for networking and fun without any
                payments or tickets whatsoever.

                Please share your thoughts on what you wish to hear or discuss during the meet-up. We'll also gather
                practical ideas for 2014. Lets have this really casual and easy-going. And do note, there are a lot of
                Vaadin and GWT superstars present in the conference so we have the possibility to have really deep
                face-to-face discussions too if needed.
            </description>
            <url>http://www.meetup.com/Vaadin-Frankfurt/events/150480172/</url>
            <location>
                <name>Radisson Blu Frankfurt</name>
                <street>Franklin Str 65</street>
                <zip>60486</zip>
                <city>Frankfurt</city>
            </location>
        </meeting>
    </schedule>
    <photocredits>
        <logo>Logo: [Ville Ingman](http://www.meetup.com/Vaadin-Frankfurt/photos/17949332/294903522/#294903522)</logo>
    </photocredits>
</usergroup>
